ILGWU. San Francisco Joint Board records 5780/065
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. San Francisco Joint Board records
1930-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
San Francisco Joint Board
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/065
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Correspondence, agreements.
The records of the San Francisco Joint Board contain three parts: general correspondence, arranged in reverse chronological order (boxes 1-2); alphabetical files (boxes 2-10); and meeting minutes of the San Francisco Joint Board, and several local unions (boxes 11-18). Records documenting the Health and Welfare Fund found in box 6 contain extensive information on members of local unions, including length of membership to the ILGWU and employment history. [Note: SSNs are throughout these and other records documenting the Health and Welfare Fund.] The local unions with minutes contained in this subseries are: 8, 101, 191, 213, and 352. Minutes for locals 8, 101, 213, 214, 215 are also found in the records of the Pacific Northwest District Council.
5492760
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 14, 2008
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 16, 2014
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Biographical / Historical
A local of cloakmakers in San Francisco was around in the first decade of the ILGWU, but was disbanded in 1913. In May 1915, members of the former local joined with an independent union of ladies' tailors to revive Local 8. The thirteen week strike of San Francisco cloakmakers in 1923 basically decimated Local 8. Brother L. Gold of Los Angeles was placed in charge of the San Francisco market and new members were organized during the next few years, but by 1928, Local 8 Cloakmakers were practically out of existence again as Communists had "captured" the organization. In 1929, those that had remained loyal to the ILGWU kept the struggling Local 8 alive. The San Francisco cloak trade at that time was small, with a few hundred cloakmakers. Local 8 was soon joined in the 1930s by new charters Dressmakers Local 101, Knitgood Workers Local 191, and Cutters Local 213. With the creation of Local 101 in 1933, Jennie Matyas came to San Francisco to help organize the dressmakers and would later serve as the education director of the San Francisco Joint Board. In the 1940s, San Francisco had a sizable dress market with two locals, 101 and 352 (General Garment Workers' Union). During this time, Henry Zacharin served as manager of the Joint Board. While smaller in scale than Los Angeles, the San Francisco garment industry was 100 percent unionized, and by 1947, the Joint Board was composed of Locals 8, 101, 213, and 352.
Garment workers in San Francisco received a 35 hour work week with the new sportswear agreement in 1953. By the mid-1950s (1956), the Joint Board was now managed by Ralph King, and the locals were signing contracts with Chinatown contractors. King served as manager until the 1960s (1962), when Cornelius Wall took over leadership of the San Francisco Joint Board. In 1967, the ILGWU and the labor movement in San Francisco joined efforts to unionize Chinatown. The 1970s (1971), saw the name of Pacific Coast Region change to Western States Region, and Mattie Jackson became manager of the Joint Board. Jackson was previously a business agent at the Koret of California shop. Complicated conditions continued to thwart organizing efforts in Chinatown, though by the mid- 1970s, in roads were being made in the shops. By 1977, Asian immigrants constituted the bulk of the non-union workforce in San Francisco. In 1980, the San Francisco Joint Board was merged into the Pacific Northwest District Council that was managed by Mattie Jackson.
Scope and Contents
Much of the correspondence for the San Francisco Joint Board is arranged chronologically by year. There is correspondence with numerous local and national organizations that the Joint Board contributed both funds and support. One organization in particular was City of Hope, in the northwest region of San Francisco. The Board sponsored a yearly Bay Area Fair in which the proceeds benefited City of Hope, and the records include meeting minutes and documents from the ILGWU City of Hope Auxiliary. There is also industry information including correspondence with contractors and manufacturers, as well as agreements with Bay Area firms. Manufacturer associations like the Associated Cloak and Suit Manufacturers, Silk and Wool Dress Manufacturers' Association, San Francisco Coat and Suit Association are represented in the records.
The collection focuses on the administrative responsibilities of the Joint Board, such as the Health and Welfare and national retirement fund, with material such as benefits and claims. The minutes of the San Francisco Joint Board meetings include roll call lists, and the later meeting minutes are inserted into forms. There are also minutes of locals that comprised the Joint Board; Local 8 Cloakmakers including both executive board and membership meetings; Local 101 Dressmakers both executive board and membership meetings, roll call, officer nominations; Local 213 Cutters; and Local 352 General Garment Workers.
A second component of the collection consists of labeled subject files. These contain member information sheets of the union health and welfare funds with individual, local, when they joined the union, listing of shops worked at with years, and are arranged alphabetically.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/115: ILGWU. Western States Region records 5780/207: ILGWU. Pacific Northwest District Council records 5780/207 AV: ILGWU. Pacific Northwest District Council audio-visual materials 5780/207 P: ILGWU. Pacific Northwest District Council photographs
Women's clothing industry -- United States.; Women's clothing industry -- California.; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- United States.; Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- California.; Clothing workers -- United States; Clothing workers -- California.; Industrial relations -- United States; Industrial relations -- California.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- San Francisco Joint Board.
5492760
- General Correspondence., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- General Correspondence., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- General Correspondence., 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- General Correspondence., 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- General Correspondence., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General Correspondence., 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- General Correspondence. [folder 1 of 2], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9a)
- General Correspondence. [folder 2 of 2], 1953 (Box 1, Folder 9b)
- General Correspondence., 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- General Correspondence., 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- General Correspondence., 1944-1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- General Correspondence., 1938-1943 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- General Correspondence., 1936-1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- General Correspondence., 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Scope and Contents
  Incl. Local 8 corres.
- General Correspondence., 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Amun Israel Housing Corporation., 1951 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Anthony's, Inc., 1952 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Auditing Department., 1949-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Auditors, Eric Hart and Julian Cohen., 1957-1965 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Audits., 1937-1941 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Local 8, 1937-40; Local 101, 1939-41.
- Census, Los Angeles Membership., 1939-1946 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Central Labor Council, AFL-CIO., 1961-1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- City of Hope. [folder 1 of 3], 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- City of Hope. [folder 2 of 3], 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- City of Hope. [folder 3 of 3], 1954-1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Cloak Firms., 1937 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Contractors (and Manufacturers). [folder 1 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Contractors (and Manufacturers). [folder 2 of 2], 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Contributions., 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Contributions., 1953-1956 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Earnings, Hourly Rates and Other Wage Data of Workers in Cloak and Dress Shops., 1930-1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Education Department, ILGWU., 1930-1955 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Elections. Local 8., 1965 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Federal Mediation and Conciliation Services (Washington, D.C.)., 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Feinberg, Basil, Attorney., 1955-1963 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Fidler, Melba (business agent)., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Firms. Betty Clyde, Inc., 1955-1967 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Firms. Ever Ready Products., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Firms. M. R. Fleischman Company., 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Firms. Gaines and Company., 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Firms. Howard C. Curtis Co., Inc., 1957-1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Firms. Marlon Inc., 1956-1960 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Firms. Simon Dress Company., 1956-1966 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Form letters., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Governor's Conference on Unemployment., 1949-1950 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Grades and Body Prices, Coats and Suits., 1934 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Grievances Against Firms., 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Health and Welfare (Vacation and Retirement) Benefits. [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Health and Welfare (Vacation and Retirement) Benefits. [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Health and Welfare Benefits., 1960-1963 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. [folder 1 of 3], 1944-1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. [folder 2 of 3], 1944-1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. [folder 3 of 3], 1944-1959 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. General Garment Manufacturers Health and Welfare Fund., 1949-1957 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Alice of California., 1948-1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Cowan, Frank Manufacturing Co., 1949-1956 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Ever Ready Products., 1947-1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Fleischman of California., 1948-1955 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Nathalie Nicole., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Reynolds Co., 1951-1956 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Trude of California., 1949-1956 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Subject files. A (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Subject files. B (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Subject files. C (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Subject files. D (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Subject files. E-F (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Subject files. G (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Subject files. H-I-J (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Subject files. K (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Subject files. L (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Subject files. M-N (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Subject files. O-P (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Subject files. Q-R (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Subject files. S (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Subject files. T (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Subject files. U-V (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Subject files. Y-Z (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. General Garment Chinese Welfare Fund (Holiday Pay Records). [folder 1 of 3], 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. General Garment Chinese Welfare Fund (Holiday Pay Records). [folder 2 of 3], 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. General Garment Chinese Welfare Fund (Holiday Pay Records). [folder 3 of 3], 1950-1953 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Health and Welfare Benefits. International Sportswear Vacation and Health Fund., 1945-1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Herbert Coat and Suit Company., 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Impartial Chairmen Cases: Morris Goldman Manufacturers Co., Ltd., 1937-1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Impartial Chairmen Cases., 1959-1966 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Koret of California, Inc., 1960-1963 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Koret of California, Inc., 1950-1952 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Labor Cost to Produce Garments and Average Wage Scales., 1939-1944 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Legal Department, ILGWU., 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Lilli Ann Corporation., 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Locals., 1949-1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Management Engineering Department., 1949-1951 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Managers' Reports., 1938-1942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Matyas, Jennie., 1953-1960 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board., 1937-1952 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- National Labor Relations Board. [folder 1 of 2], 1938-1950 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- National Labor Relations Board. [folder 2 of 2], 1938-1950 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Negotiations and Agreements., 1948-1958 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Pacific Coast Garment Manufacturers., 1949-1965 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Pacific Coast Office, ILGWU., 1942-1965 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Parolees., 1956-1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- President's Office: David Dubinsky., 1951-1956 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- President's Office: David Dubinsky., 1948-1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- President's Office: David Dubinsky., 1934-1947 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Puerto Rico., 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Research Department., 1948-1951 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 1 of 2], 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 2 of 2], 1960-1963 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 1 of 2], 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Retirement Funds. Coat, Suit and Dress Industries in San Francisco. [folder 2 of 2], 1954-1959 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Rubenstein and Hawkins, Attorneys., 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- San Francisco. Coat and Suit Association, and Silk and Wool Dress Manufacturers Association. [folder 1 of 2], 1943-1964 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- San Francisco. Coat and Suit Association, and Silk and Wool Dress Manufacturers Association. [folder 2 of 2], 1943-1964 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- San Francisco Labor Council., 1947-1964 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Shop Meetings. Attendance records and minutes. [folder 1 of 2], 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Shop Meetings. Attendance records and minutes. [folder 2 of 2], 1962-1965 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Social Security Administration., 1956-1965 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Stulberg, Louis., 1961-1965 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Tobriner and Lazarus, Attorneys., 1947-1952 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Umhey, Frederick F., 1945-1951 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Union Label Department., 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Union Medical Panel, San Francisco., 1947-1953 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Wage Stabilization Board (National War Labor Board)., 1944-1946 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- War Labor Board., 1943-1945 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1941-1942 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1943-1944 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1945-1946 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1956-1957 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1958 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1960 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1961-1962 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1963-1964 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1965 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1966 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Joint Board Meetings., 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Joint Board Appeals Committee., 1951 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Joint Board Emergency Assistance Committee., 1954-1961 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Joint Relations Committee (Union and Association)., 1938 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1934 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  January 29, 1934-October 17, 1934
- Minutes, Local 8., 1934-1935 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  October 22, 1934-May 29, 1935.
- Minutes, Local 8., 1935-1936 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  June 5, 1935-May 25, 1936.
- Minutes, Local 8., 1936 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  June 1, 1936-December 18, 1936
- Minutes, Local 8., 1937 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1938 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1941-1942 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1943-1944 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1945-1946 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1947-1948 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1949-1950 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1951 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1952-1953 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1954-1955 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1956-1957 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1958 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1959 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1960-1961 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1964-1965 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1966 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Local 8., 1969 (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1935 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1936 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1937 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Local 101, Lingerie Section., 1936-1937 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1938 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1939 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1940 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1941-1942 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1943-1944 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1945-1946 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1947-1948 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1949-1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1953-1954 (Box 16, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1955-1956 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1957-1958 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1959 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1960-1961 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1962-1965 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1966-1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1968 (Box 16, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Local 101., 1969 (Box 16, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Local 101, Oakland Section., 1967-1969 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Local 191, Knitgoods Workers Union., 1942-1947 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1935-1956 (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1940-1941 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1942-1944 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1945-1946 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1947 (Box 17, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1952-1956 (Box 17, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1957 (Box 17, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1958 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1959 (Box 17, Folder 12)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1960-1961 (Box 18, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1962-1963 (Box 18, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1964-1965 (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Minutes, Local 213., 1966-1969 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Local 213, Grievance Committee., 1957-1961 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  Includes related correspondence.
- Minutes, Local 352, General Garment Workers., 1954-1957 (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Miscellaneous., 1939-1941 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  Organization unknown.